Today we will talk about health insurance plans of
Scenery Citizens. So, we will compare the top four health
insurance plans of Scenery Citizens in
2023. First is
Neem Bhup Scenery, First is Test
Star Health, Red Carpet, Third is ICC
Lombard, Golden
Scenery. So, we will talk about the similarities in these plans, what are the
differences,
what are the eligibility criteria, what are the features
and how much will the premium be
for you. So, before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My
name is Gurleen Kaur. Look, I am a certified
financial planner and every week I
bring videos for you so that your personal
financial life and insurance
journey becomes your happy because
our company's tagline is also creating a
belt of happiness. Also, I would like to
highlight that I have 18 years of experience
with the insurance industry and the knowledge that I am
sharing with you is
because of this experience. So, now we will talk about the
plans and will compare the plans of
Scenery Citizens.
You are looking for a policy for your parents
if you are a senior citizen, then your
search ends here, let us list these plans for you in a
very
simple and easy way by shortcut and present them in
front of you with comparison
and fourth is Manipal Singh Prime Senior
Citizen, so first we will talk about the
claim settlement ratio and cut claim ratio of the company,
so Nava's claim settlement
ratio is 90.12% and the incurred claim ratio is
62.12%, Star Health's claim settlement
ratio is 81.71% and the incurred claim ratio is
87.08%, ICC Lombard's claim
settlement ratio is 88.67% and their claim
ratio is 91.67%, Manipal Singh's claim
settlement ratio is
189.8% and their claim ratio is 76.17%
because senior citizens generally have some
medical or the other problem.  There are conditions if you
go higher, then there are some
lifestyle problems or some medical conditions.
So these plans are specifically
made for senior citizens only
because the undertaking is liner. These
policies are easily issued as compared to
standard policies available in the
market. I
would like to tell you that the free policy medical check is
not a medical checkup. There is no mandatory
medical checkup in the policy. The
policy will be issued on the basis of the declaration you give.
BP is not made in your health also. There is
no medical checkup in the policy
but if you get these charts tested and submit them then
you can get a 10% discount on the premium.
These charts are
stress plate report, BP report,
sugar blue and urine test and blue urine
creatinine. If you submit these test reports
before the policy is closed then the
medical checkup in the policy is
not required anyway but you will be given a 10%
discount on the premium
in ICC Lombard Golden Sale if you  If you are
entering the policy before 65 years,
then there is no medical checkup in the policy.
Manipal Singh Prime Scenery also does
not have a medical checkup in the policy. Now let's talk about the
minimum time limit. The minimum time limit
in Niwabu Pass India First is five lakhs and the maximum is
25 lakhs. So, two variants are available
flat. Next, we will talk about the
minimum entry limit in Star Health Red Carpet. The maximum entry limit is ₹1 lakh.
In Golden Steel, the minimum entry limit is five lakhs and the maximum entry limit is 50 lakhs.
In Manipal Singh Classical Elite Classic, the minimum entry limit is
three lakhs and the maximum
entry limit is five lakhs and the maximum entry limit is 50 lakhs. Now let's talk about the minimum entry limit and the maximum entry limit.
In Nava Purpose Other Air First, the minimum
entry limit is 61 years and the maximum is 75 years. Meaning, if you are between 61 and 75, then you can take the policy. Similarly, the minimum entry limit of Star Health is 60 and the maximum entry limit is 75.  The
minimum
entry age is 56 and there
is no maximum limit, you can enter this policy till any later.
In Manipal Singh Prime Scenery, the minimum entry age is 56 and the
maximum is 75. Policy Type:
You can take all these policies in individual, family, floor term,
multi-individual form.
Policy 10 and 1 Air, 2 Air, 3 Air and 10 Air, all
four policies are available in it, meaning if you
want, take a one-year policy. Now if you want to
pack the front premium for 2 years or 3 years, then
it is called multi-
tenure policy. In that, the company has given you some
discount if you pay the premium of 2 years or 3 years
together. Now let's talk about
Platinum having a single private room.
In Star Health Red Carpet, if you have a
policy of ₹1 to ₹5, then 1% discount will be given on
your room rent. If you have a policy of ₹7.5 to 10 lakh, then the
limit is ₹5000. If you have a policy of 15 lakh, then ₹
7000 or 20 lakh policy.  If you have a
policy of ₹8500 and 25 lakhs then the
room limit is ₹10000 ICC In Lombard Golden
Steel, if your sum is less than 10 lakhs
then your room is on twin sharing
basis If your sum is above 10 lakhs then you have eligibility for single private single
room In Manipal Singh D Prime Scenery, however
if you are going in a higher category room,
if the room is not available
in the hospital then there will be only proportional
reduction in the case, the entire expenses will
not be deducted from you, only the
proportionate amount which will be the difference of the room
and the difference of other things will have to be
paid by you On higher room
upgrade if the room is not available now let's
talk about ICU room rent, it will be
paid first In Star Red Carpet,
if you have a policy of 1 lakh to 10 lakhs
then 2% of summed is your room rent
If you have a policy of more than 15 lakhs then
ICC will be done on actual
In both Lombard Golden Cell and Manipal Singh
Prime Scenery, the ICU room
rent will be paid as per the actual bill.
Domestic hospitalization
is also covered in all four plans. Basically,
due to the advancement of science, there are some
procedures which do
not require 24-hour hospitalization. So,
domestic hospitalization is covered in all four plans.
If the patient has to be admitted at home or hospitalized at home, there are
two conditions for the patient, one is that a
bed is not available in the hospital. The second
condition is that the patient is so critical that he
cannot be taken to the hospital. So,
domestic hospitalization is also available in all four plans.
Now let's talk about refill benefit,
restore benefit, rest statement benefit. It is called
by different names in different policies, but it is the
same. So,
your refill benefit is
not available in the Gold plan, it
is available in the Platinum plan.  Unlimited number of times for
other illnesses, that is, suppose you have taken
insurance of Rs. 10 lakhs, you have
taken platinum variant, your Rs. 10 lakhs gets exhausted
and you definitely need to refill
hospitalizations, every one of these will be refilled up to Rs.
10 lakhs and this can happen
multiple number of times.
Refill benefit is not available in Star Health Red Carpet.
Refill is also available in ICC Lombard Health Advantage, it is a slightly different
concept, let me tell you,
in ICC Lombard, if you have to refill hospitalizations for any illness, then
one for every
other illness, unlimited number of times
in your refill is available. Refill is not
available in Manipal Singh Prime Scenery as well as Classic,
which is their elite variant, in which
unlimited number of times for
other illnesses is covered, pre and post hospitalization
expenses are those expenses which are incurred
before or after hospitalization,
but for these illnesses, hospitals for this thing are
free hospitalizations.  You can reverse the expenses of
16 days post 18 days in Kar Health
Red Carpet, Pari hospital expense is of 30
days and 7% off of the post hospital
maximum ten thousand rupees
can be claimed post hospital expense ICC
Lombard Golden Seal is 6180 Priyanka
post hospital expense in Manipal Singh
Prime Scenery if you are taking classic variant
then 360 and if you are taking elite variant
then 60 days and 90 days free enforce
hospitalization expense you can invest
Emergency Road Ambulance In NIFA Scenery First
Plan hospital will be given at ₹2000
Forward Ambulance Star Health Red Carpet has
maximum ₹3000 in all it is
decided according to the shortest in all Maximum
₹3000 on hospital
1% off on time maximum ₹10000 will be paid
on
hospital is emergency and ambulance is
covered Emergency AV Ambulance is only
for an accurate use
in such area  Wherever there is no road ambulance,
there is no power and the ambulance is charged
at Rs. 2.5 lakh. This is not available in Star Health Red Carpet.
ICC Lombard Golden Shield
covers up to Time Shot and Manipal Singh. It is
not available in the classic variant. It is
available in the elite variant. The maximum tax is Rs. 10
lakh. Now let's talk about the no claim bonus. Nava
Bhopa Scenery Nuclear bonus is given every year at
10%. Maximum you will get is 100%. And
remember here that it will not be reduced, meaning it is
not a clock pack. If you get the bonus only once in your job, then
that amount will remain with you.
Meaning if your 10 lakh policy reaches 20 lakhs, by
doing 10% in 10 years, then
it will remain at Rs. 20 lakh only. It will not be reduced.
Star Health Red Carpet does
not have the concept of no claim bonus. ICC Lombard Golden
Shield also gives 10% every year and you will get no
claim bonus. If you do not take any claim, then you will get 10% every
year, maximum it will go up to 100%.  And there will be
no reduction in these cases of future plans
Manipal Signal Prime Scenery has
different concept of knock bonus in Classic and Elite. In
Classic you will get knock bonus only when
you do not have a claim, 10% per year
maximum 100% and it will not be reduced.
In Elite for future plans you have
guaranteed cumulative bonus irrespective of
claim. Your policy will increase by 10% every year which is
loyalty addition.
Modern treatments and
robotic surgery are available in all these four plans.
In Neem Bhupa Scenery First, in Star Health
and ICC Lo But Golden Seat, there are some
supplements which you can prefer.
Policy wording and in Manipal Signal Prime
Scenery, there is a time shot government. Now let's
talk whether there are any supplements in the policy
or not. We will talk about all limits.
Now there are no sublimits in Scenery First, no
specific exclusions
on any other treatment, there is no
supplement of any kind and in Star Health
Red Carpet there is a sub-limit on some diseases.  There are limits on
what diseases are those? They are
cerebrovascular accident, cardiovascular
disease, cancer including chemotherapy,
radiotherapy, medical renal disease including
dialysis treatment, breaks of long
bonus. There are some of these, you can check in the policy wording.
Next is ICC
Lombard Golden Seal, there are limits on all these things,
along with cataract,
also there are limits on all of them. There is no limit
on anything in Manipal Singh's Prime Scenario.
Organ
donor expense
is covered in ICC Lombard Golden Seal up to Rs 10 lakh. Manipal
Singh has up to Rs 10 lakh and tax in Prime Scenario.
OPD expense is
not taxed in Animas Pa Scenario First.
OPD expense is covered in Star Health Rate
Carpet at Rs 200 as per concentration,
maximum Rs 26,100
in individual policy and Rs 4400 in family policy.  It will be
given in the total policy itself. There is a
big tax in ICC also. OPD
expenses are not taxed and in Manipal Singh you can add a rider in which is
Health 360 where you
can do OPD. AYUSH is an
alternative treatment like it is called
Ayurvedic Unani principles, Homeopathy.
In their hospital you are given a big tax of
Rs 500. If this
policy is available in Gold then the maximum is Rs 10,000
and you can claim from
Star Health Red Carpet. If the
policy is above Rs 10 lakh then the maximum
limit is Rs 4500. Complimentary tax is given
in ICC Lombard.
Manipal Singh has just covered it. Now let's talk about
co-payment. Is the
option of co-payment also available in these plans or is it
mandatory, let's see further.
In Megapix India First you have the option of
making a co-payment of 10% up to 20-30% and
zero the day after.  Payment is also available. If you do
not want to make any payment and want to pay the entire
bail to the insurance company, then you
can make payment at zero tax. Mera Star
Health Red has a mandatory 30% copay mark, which
means you will have to share 30% in every claim. For example, if there is a
claim of Rs 1 lakh, then
you will have to pay Rs 30,000. If it is Rs 70,000, then
you can make payment up to 10%, 20%, 30%. I
would like to tell you that by doing this
your premium gets reduced because
if you are sharing the bill, the more you
pay, the less your premium will be.
Now let us talk about the deductible option. The
deductible option is basically that
you will first pay the adaptable amount in the claim and
after that the claim will be settled.  Meaning
if you have taken a deductible thing for ₹1 lakh
policy and your time limit is ₹10, then if any
claim comes in a year, this is an annual aggregate
deductible, so if any claim comes, then
first ₹1 lakh will have to be paid on top of that, the
insurance company will bear whatever your
time is and as per the policy terms and conditions, the
premium comes down significantly due to the deductible,
we will talk about which
companies have the deductible option available,
in the first scenario, you can get an adaptable option
with 20% off, that is,
if the policy is of 5 lakhs, then 1 lakh is
deductible, if it is of 10 lakhs, then 2 lakhs, if it is of
25 lakhs, then 5 lakhs
is deductible, this is for those who already have some
option available, some backup or
who want to reduce their premium, then the
deductible option is a very suitable relief and a
relief in the long term financial terms as well, the
reductible option is not available in Star Health Red Carpet, for
example  I had mentioned about
mandatory 30% cooperation on every claim. Due to this, a
reductible option is also available in Golden Seal, of which
20% off is
also available in Manipal Singh Prime Scenery.
Now let's talk about non
-payable items. So for non-payable items,
you can add a rider from Nimko Pass India First.
Star Health does not have any rider for non-payable items, nor are
non-payable items covered.
In ICC Lombard Golden Seal, you
can add a Claim Protector rider, which will cover
non-payable consumer items.
Similarly, you can add Manipal Singh Health 360, in
which non-payable items will be covered.
Now let's talk about riders.
You can add a rider in Nimko Pass India First. There
is no rider available in Flipkart Star Health.
ICC Lombard Golden Seal has a Claim
Protector Rider and Care Management
Program. You can add those too.
Manipal Singh has some riders.  It
is available, which I would like to tell you that
you can add Health 360, through which
you can avail non-payable lights OPD coverage. There is
also a room upgrade rider, through which if you
want to add any room in it, you
can also take that rider. If
you
want to add unlimited refill benefit in Classic, then you can also add on premium for that.
Unlimited refill benefit is already included in Elite.
Reduction in waiting period means
you can reduce the waiting period for any existing disease to 90 days. It is a
very good option
for senior citizens who want that
they do not have to wait for any existing disease.
Even after 90 days, the
existing disease will be covered if you add on this
rider for an extra
premium. Now we will talk about
exclusions and waiting periods. The initial
waiting period is there in all four policies.
You cannot do any plain hospitalization for 30 days. The
specified
exclusions which are listed on I RADA
which is a list of slow growing illnesses are
not covered in these four policies but 24
months like stone, cataract, hernia,
piles, five provide need an placement, these are
some of the things which are included in slow growing illnesses,
these will not be covered in any policy for two years.
Now let's talk about the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases. The waiting period in First is 2
years in Star Health Red Carpet, there is 1 year in
ICC Lombard Golden Style, there is 2
years in Manipal Singh and Prime
Scenery also there is a waiting period of 2 years
but free existing disease but you can
reduce your waiting period.
Look at the additional premium, 290 days. The most
important thing is that we will talk about the premium.
Here I have taken a premium of Rs. 61, I have
calculated it further and have taken a range of Rs. 10 lakh
and we will talk about the premium of John Maa.  If you are
taking an individual premium of Rs
61 lakh and Rs 10 lakh, then
I have not added any rider here. So, if there is an
apple to apple comparison, you
can choose your policy. It
comes free of cost Rs 47322. If you take 20%
co-payment, then the premium comes Rs
39615. If you take 2 Last Adaptable, then the premium
comes free in 10 lakh policy Rs
1783. In Start Health Red Carpet, any
deductible or co-payment option is mandatory. If
deductible option is
not available, then it is straight, its
premium of Rs 10 lakh comes Rs 25223.
In ICC Lombard Golden Steel, the premium will come
with 20% co-payment Rs 59617 and with 2 lakh table Rs
28380. In Manipal Singh Na Prime Scenery,
Classic Plane, its premium will come Rs
35304 then 0% co-payment Rs 2843 with 20% co-
payment and in Elite Plane
377490 with payment on the same day and 30000 with
200 copayments on the same day and with the reductible option, the
premium reduces considerably, you
can do that. So these were the top
four Scenic Citizens plans from my side available in 2023
which you can see for yourself or for your parents. You can
ask any question regarding the plans and can reach out in the comment section. If you want to
buy these plans, you
can also recharge us on our WhatsApp number or email ID. If you
want to give any feedback, please do give it and before going, a
quick reminder if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the right
information and the right time, you will meet
quickly. Take care bye bye.